Hi, I am Bob Tabor with www.learnvisualstudio.net.
大家好，我是来自www.learnvisualstudio.net的Bob Tabor
In this lesson we will begin learning about the XAML syntax.
在这节课程中我们将要开始学习XAML语法
Honestly it's pretty easy to figure out the absolute basis of XAML just by looking at it.
诚心说一句要弄懂XAML的基础你只需要看上一眼
I mean I can imagine that whatever you saw in the previous lesson
我意思是我能相像你们上一节课所看到的
you were able to at least figure out the correlation between the tags,
足够让你们搞清楚了标签、
the properties and what you saw in the visual designer, right?
属性和你在可视化设计器中扭看到的，它们之间的关系，对吧
Well what I want to accomplish is to talk about
那么我要完成的任务就是讲解一下
some of the features and functions that may not be so obvious at the first glance.
那些一眼看上去不那么明显的功能和方法
So we will take a couple of parts at this short videos
在这个简短的视频中我们会分成几个部分来进行讲解
that when combined together will give a pretty throughout understanding of XAML
合起来后对XAML会有一个自始至终的认识
and how it all works .
并能了解它是如何工作的
In this first lesson we are gonna talk about the purpose and the nature of XAML,
在第一课，我们来讨论一下XAML的用途和本质。
especially in comparison to C#.
尤其是要跟C#对比一下
Then the next few lessons
然后接下来的几个课程
we are going to talk about the special features in XAML.
我们将会讨论XAML的特殊功能
Little hidden features of the language that,
这门语言一些小而隐秘的功能
again, may not be obvious when you first start looking at it
再说一次，当你第一次看的时候可能真的不明显
So my aim is that by the end of the first several lessons
因此，我的目标是在这几个课程结束时
you're going to have enough knowledge that you can look at the XAML that we write together
你有足够的知识看清楚我们一起写的XAML
and in the remainder of this series you are going to be able to take a pretty good guess of what it's trying to do
并且在这个系列的其他课程里可以很好的猜测它要做什么
before I even explain what it does.
在我进行解释之前
Alright, so first of all let's talk about what XAML is.
好了，首先让我们来谈谈XAML是什么
In the previous lesson I made a passing remark about
有前面几节课中我短暂的提到
how XAML looks similar to HTML and that's no accidents.
XAML是如此的类似于HTML，并且这绝非偶然
XAML is really just XML, the eXtensible Markup Language.
XAML实际就是XML，可扩展标记语言
I will explained that relationship in just a moment,
我只会简短的解释一下它们的关系
but at a higher level
从更高级别上看
XML looks a lot like HTML and so much that they share a common ancestry.
XML看起来跟HTML很像，它们共享同一个祖先
Whereas HTML is specific to structuring a web page document
然而HTML特定于构建网页文档
XML a little bit more generic in nature
XML本质上更具通用性
and by generic I mean that you can use it for any purpose that you decide
我意思是你可以将它用于任何目的
and you can define the names and the elements of the attributes to suit your needs
你可以定义属性的名字和元素来满足你的需求
Now the past developers have used XML for things like storing application settings
现在，开发者们经常用XML来存储应用的设置
or using it as a means of transferring data between two systems that were never intend to work together
或者当作一种手段用于两个毫不相关的系统交换数据
And to use XML you start off by defining what's called the schema
使用XML，先要了解所谓的“模式”
which declares the proper names of the elements and their attributes
它为元素定义合适的名字以及属性
and so schema is kind of like a contract that two parties agreed to,everybody agrees
“模式”就像一份双方同意的合同，所有人都同意
Both the producer of XML and the consumer of XML
无论是XML的生产者还是XML的消费者
to write and read the XML to conform to those rules set forth in the contract,I mean, the schema.
读取和写入XML都要遵循“合同”中的规定，我意思其实是指“模式”
And now that they both agree
现在，他们都同意
that they're working in the same rule of the same contract and communicate with each other
在同一份合同下遵循相同的规则来工作、互相沟通
So, a schema is a really important part of XML
因此，“模式”对XML来说是很重要的一部分
and just keep in mind 'cuz we will come back to that in just a moment
并且你们要记住它，因为我们很快就会回到这个话题上
XAML is a special usage of XML
XAML是XML的特殊用法
Obviously we see, at least in this case
很明显的，我们能看到，至少在我们这里这种情况下
XAML has something to do with defining a user interface for our for application
XAML与定义我们应用的用户界面有关
so now we got it feels a lot like HTML but there's a big difference
这时我们感觉它跟HTML很像，但实际它们有很大的不同
XAML is actually used to create instances of classes and set values of their properties.
XAML实际是用来创建类的实例并且为它们的属性赋值
So for example in the previous lesson we created a little hello world application
因此，比如说我们上节课创建的"hello world"小应用
I can expand on that here just give it a little more design
我可以在它上边进行扩展，只需要为它添加一点儿“设计”
I added a button and notice that I put all the attributes on separate lines and now we can see
我添加一个按钮，注意我将属性都放到单独的一行。现在我们能看到
hopefully the definition will look a bit better
希望这样子定义会好看一些
I'm actually getting more room here
这里我需要更多一点空间
We are going to rely less and less on the visual designer
我们要尽量少的依赖可视化设计器
In fact we may start to get rid of it completely
实际上我们完全可以摆脱它
but you can see here that I created a red button called "click me"
你看到这里我创建了一个红色按钮命名为“click me"
and there's also a MessageTextBlock that will appear below
同样的有个MessageBlock会出现在下面
So it's very much like what we did before,I am just starting over from scratch
所以它跟我们之前做的非常相似，只是我从头做了一遍
what I want to do is well first of all let's...
首先做什么好叫呢
let's go let's go ahead and take a look at the code behind
让我们往前，看看后面的代码
and we'll set the TextBlock equal to "What is XAML?"
我们设这个TextBlock的值等于"What is XAML"
the topic of this lesson, whenever you click the button
也就是这个课程的题目，只要你点击了这个按钮
So let's run the application briefly
让我们简单的运行一下这个应用
just to show that there is nothing up my sleeve
只是展示一下我袖子里边没有东西
And click it and we get the result
点击，获得结果
Great, okay now what I want to do
非常好，现在我想做的
just to demonstrate how XMAL works
只是展示XAML是如何工作的
is actually comment out this button control
实际上就是我注释掉的这个按钮控制的
and I'll use the syntax that you would use if you're familiar with HTML at how to comment out things
我现在用的这个，跟你们熟悉的HTML中的注释是一样的
It's just this open bracket
用一个开尖括号
*** mark, dash, dash
**标记，破折号，破折号
to start the comment section
来开启一个区域的注释
And then to end the comment section you just do dash, dash,
在注释区域的末尾，你只需要破折号、破折号
closing angle bracket like so
以及像这样的闭尖括号
and you can see that in Visual Studio code editor that it appears green by default
然后你能看到在Visual Studio代码编辑区它默认变成了绿色
Okay, so now that we've got rid of it
好的，现在我们已经去掉了它
what I'm gonna do is actually, come back over here
我将要做的实际是回到这里
well actually a couple of things
实际上还有几件事
I already gave this a name
这里我已经给了一个name属性
but by default whenever you create a new project
但是默认情况下，创建一个工程的时候
the grid does not have a name
这个grid是没有name属性的
I gave it the name LayoutGrid Because that is *** what it is actually doing for us.
我给它起了个名字叫"LayoutGrid"因为它恰当的描述了我们现在做的事
And then the other thing I want to do is whenever the page loads
那么现在我想做的另一件事是当页面加载出来时
so I'm going to find the Loaded event
我要找到"loaded"事件
I'm gonna create a new event handler call Page_Loaded
我将创建一个新的事件处理程序叫做"Page_Loaded"
and use the F12 key on my keyboard to pop that open and the code behind
按下键盘上的F12键打开它后面的代码
And so now I'm gonna write code
现在我要写代码了
that will execute whenever the page has loaded in the memory
它将会在页面加载加载到内存里时运行
And this's going to take me a little bit
这里将要花费我一点儿时间
and hopefully you'll see why and it'll prove what I'm trying to explain here
希望在我解释的时候你们能明白为什么以及预测到它会发生什么
So I might even just kind of start this out
我只写点开头
and fast forward near the end of this typing exercise
然后快速到达这次“打字练习”的结尾
I don't recommend that you do this
我不建议你们也这么做
Okay so it took me about two mins to type all this out
好了，花了我大约两分钟把这些全打出来
I am not the slowest typist in the world
我不是世界上最慢的打字员
but this is pretty fit typing
但这还是很适合拿来练习的
and tell us how to not make a few mistakes along the way
并且能告诉我们如何在写代码的道路上减少错误
but the point of this is if we actually run the application
但这里的要点是，如果我运行这个程序
I wanna show you what it does
我来给你展示一下它会发生什么
Hey it created a red button
嘿，它创建了一个红色按钮
almost identical in fact is identical to the one that we defined in XAML
几乎是一致的实际就是跟我们在XAML中定义的完全一致
and if we click it it gives me the same results
如果我们点击它，它给我们一样的结果
So the point I'm making here is that
所以我这里的关键是
it took all of this C# code
它花费了这里所有的C#代码
to do what I was able to do in basically just one line of code
做了我基本上一行代码就能搞定的事
Now I spaced it out over several lines
这里我分割成了几行
but you can see that the C# version of this is much more verbose
但你也看到了C#版本要明显冗长很多
And then secondly what we are really doing when we are defining elements and attribute in XAML
其次，我们在XAML中定义元素和属性
is that we're creating new instances of classes in the Universal Windows Platform API
实际上就是在Universal Windows Platform API中创建类
and defining and setting their attributes and properties just like we're doing here in this code, alright
定义、设置它们的属性、特性跟我们这里代码做的事是一样的
By the way, before I forget
顺便说一句，差点忘了
if you want to follow along and do this exercise yourself
如果你想跟着做这个练习
I will add the I already have the Before where we started out
我会添加，我们开始之前就有了的代码
and I'll add this code that I just typed in the After
也会添加我输入过之后的代码
so you'll be able to get in this project "WhatIsXAML"
然后你就能获得这个名为“XAML是什么”的项目了
So the important take away is this
重要的要记住的一点是
that XAML is simply a way to create instances of classes
XAML是一种简单的创建类的实例的方法
and set those objects properties in a much more simplified succinct syntax
并能使用简洁很多的语法来设置这些对象的属性
(It) took us 12 lines of code, 13 lines of code C#
花费了12行，13行C#代码
only took one line of XAML
却只需要1行XAML代码
Even if I did separated it out, it's still until much shorter than would have been had I use C# to create all of my object
尽管我分割开了，但仍然要比使用C#来创建我所有的对象要短
Furthermore whenever I do use XAML
此外，
I get this automatic feedback here in the visual designer in the preview pane
我还能在可视化设计器的预览窗格中得到自动反馈
So I can see the impact of my changes instantly if I choose to work like that
所以如果我那样子做，我就能及时看到我的更改带来的效果
So in the case of the procedure C# that I wrote
所以，在编写C#的过程中
I have to run the application each time that I wanted to see how my tweets to the code actually work
我就不用每次都启动程序来看我提交的代码工作得如何了
So okay that's it, that's the point of this lesson
好了，就这样吧，这就是本节课的重点
Two fold, one that XAML is just a specific flavor of XML
有两点，一是XAML只是特定格式的XML
It follows all the rules of XML
它遵循所有XML的规则
Somebody defines the schema
人们再定义一种“模式”
a contract, and then both the producer and consumer of the XML agree to the contract
也就相当于一个条款合约，然后无论是XML的生产者还是消费者都去遵守它
and then they can begin to work together, konwing that they are pretty much on the same page
这样在同一个页面上他们就能一起工作，并且互相了解得更多
Now in this case, the contract is XAML and it was defined by Microsoft
我们现在这种情况，条款就是由Microsoft定义的XAML
the producer of the XML is you, me and visual studio
XML的生产者是你们，我，还有Visual Studio
and then the consumer of the XML
然后，XML的消费者
is the compiler which will turn our code into an executable that will run in Windows 10
是将我们的代码变成windows 10可执行文件的编译器
And so that's the first point
好了这就是第一点
The second point of this lesson was that XAML is an easy way to create instances of classes and set the properties
本节课第二点是XAML是一种简单的创建类的实例并设置属性的方法
and sure you can do this all in C#, but it's much more verbose
当然你也可以用C#来完成，但要冗长得多
and you would lose the design time tooling that we've become accustom to in here, two or three short videos
你也无法享用在这两三个视频中已经熟悉了的设计工具
Okay so actually this example that we just created
好了，实际上我们创建的这个小例子
has a few other little interesting features of XAML that I want to explain a little bit further
还有其他一些有趣的XAML小特性，但我想后面一点再说
and so I'll start that process in the very next lesson.
Thank you
最近的课我很快就会就此展开，谢谢！